<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/marcmagn1/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/marcmagn1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-12-06T14:02:38+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/marcmagn1/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Marcmagn1</title><subtitle>Marcmagn1's personal blog - geekeries, interesting tidbits from light-programmming to travels, including (but not limited to) Infosec, Product Management, OSINT, Raspberry Pi... </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Hello, World! (From Jekyll on a Pi controlled locally by an Ipad)</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/marcmagn1/geekeries/2019/12/06/Hello-World-From-Jekyll-Pi-Pad.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello, World! (From Jekyll on a Pi controlled locally by an Ipad)" /><published>2019-12-06T11:29:39+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-06T11:29:39+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/marcmagn1/geekeries/2019/12/06/Hello-World-From-Jekyll-Pi-Pad</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/marcmagn1/geekeries/2019/12/06/Hello-World-From-Jekyll-Pi-Pad.html">&lt;p&gt;Et voilà! It’s live! 😅&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a small struggle but I finally managed to complete the workflow I had in mind to produce this first post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;- Control a Raspian-powered Raspberry Pi 4 from an Ipad over SSH over USB-C
- Run Jekyll on the Pi to generate and serve this static website
- Run samba file-sharing from the Pi to expose the website files over the network and access them from the Ipad native apps
- Edit the files from Textastic or any other app on the Ipad
- Access the local preview of the website served locally by the Pi from the Ipad browser
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might seem complex, but when everything has been setup, it’s butter-smooth!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ipad is lightning-fast, the Pi always available (connected over USB-C, it does not need an internet connection), and the whole setup is super portable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know… One would think that the ordeal could be easily avoided if everything was running on a Macbook, Microsoft Surface or anything with a desktop grade OS. Fair enough, one would be right!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Call me masochist but I beleve that overcoming the  limitations presented by the Ipad and Pi and come up with something that works is interesting enough to justify the oddity of the setup: after all, it’s when facing adversity that creativity is fueled! 
And to be frank, it’s actually stimulating and focusing to work from IpadOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you would like a tutorial on the setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assess alternatives to Textastic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add version control / Working Copy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Explore IOS shortcut to create new posts / control Jekyll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/marcmagn1/assets/publishing_setup.png&quot; alt=&quot;Publishing setup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Et voilà! It’s live! 😅</summary></entry></feed>